(
"ai_sub_version": "3.0.2",
"generated_at": "2026-06-29T00:52:51.580762",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
白銀ノエル 生誕祭2025 3D新衣装お披露目
[Title: Shirogane Noel Birthday Celebration 2025: 3D New Outfit Reveal]
白銀ノエル
Shirogane Noel
百鬼あやめ
Nakiri Ayame
大空スバル
Oozora Subaru
兎田ぺこら
Usada Pekora
不知火フレア
Shiranui Flare
宝鐘マリン
Houshou Marine
雪花ラミィ
Yukihana Lamy
角巻わため
Tsunomaki Watame
白銀ノエル生誕祭2025 睡夢 -suimu-
[Title: Shirogane Noel Birthday Celebration 2025: Suimu]
目指せよ快眠
Aim for sound sleep
勝ち取れ安眠
Win peaceful sleep
いざ夢の世界へ
Let's go to the dream world
理想の眠りを求めて
Seeking the ideal sleep
さあ
Come on,
始めよう
let's start,
おやすみ
good night.
ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep
私は囚われの姫
I am a captive princess
魔王の城の中で
Inside the Demon King's castle
独り閉じ込められては
Locked away alone
毎日ひたすらに眠ってます
Sleeping earnestly every day.
今宵も
Tonight again,
布団に入り
I crawl into the futon,
スヤリスト生活
Sleepy Life.
枕もシーツも
Both the pillow and the sheets
硬くて眠れない
Are hard, I can't sleep.
(君も寝具にしてやろうか!)
(Shall I turn you into bedding too!)
目指せよ快眠
Aim for sound sleep
勝ち取れ安眠
Win peaceful sleep
いざ夢の世界へ
Let's go to the dream world
ふかふかの枕手に入れて
Getting a fluffy pillow,
この疲れ癒したい
I want to heal this fatigue.
恐れず前進
Advance without fear,
ほぐせよ全身
loosen up your whole body.
瞼を閉じたなら
Once you close your eyelids,
すべすべのシーツの上で
on the smooth sheets,
さあ始めよう
come on, let's start,
おやすみ
good night.
ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep
私は囚われの姫
I am a captive princess
悲鳴が響く夜に
In a night where screams echo,
一人で檻を抜け出し
escaping the cage alone
今日もお散歩へと
and going for a walk today too.
行ってきます
I'm off.
幾多の試練を越えて
Overcoming many trials,
新たな寝具の元へ
towards new bedding.
マグマで
With magma,
猛毒で
with deadly poison,
死んでも眠りたい
I want to sleep even if I die.
城ごと寝具にしてやろうか！
Shall I turn the whole castle into bedding!
掴めよ快眠 疲れて安眠
Grab a good sleep, tired, a sound sleep.
いざ夢の向こうへ
Now, to the other side of the dream.
ハイテク目覚まし手に入れて
Getting a high-tech alarm clock,
気持ちよく目覚めたい
I want to wake up feeling good.
まだまだ前進 華麗に変身
Still moving forward, transforming beautifully.
ごはんを食べたなら
If I have eaten a meal,
魔法のベッドにダイブして
diving into a magic bed,
さあ 始めよう
now, let's start.
おやすみ
Good night.
明日はもっと 今日よりずっと
Tomorrow, more than today, by far,
いい夢みれるかな
I wonder if I can have a good dream.
ふわふわの羽根に包まれて
Wrapped in fluffy feathers,
ココロゆくまで眠りたい
I want to sleep to my heart's content.
目指せよ快眠 勝ち取れ安眠
Aim for a good sleep, win a sound sleep.
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, to the dream world,
理想の眠りを求めて
seeking the ideal sleep,
さあ 始めよう
now, let's start.
おやすみ
Good night.
もう あと5分
Just five more minutes...
おやすみ
Good night.
ノンレム睡眠レム睡眠...
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep...
スヤァ
Zzz...
うーん！はい！こんまっする！
Mmm... Yes! Hi, Konmassuru!
ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルです！
I'm Shirogane Noel of Hololive Gen 3!
本日はライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to my live concert today!
そしてハッシュタグはこちら！
And here is the hashtag!
白銀ノエル生誕祭2025たくさんスクショしてSNSに投稿してください！
Please take lots of screenshots and post them on SNS with #ShiroganeNoelBirthdayFestival2025!
今日のライブのテーマなんですが、まあ見ての通りね、
As for the theme of today's live concert, as you can see,
睡眠安眠癒やしライブとなっております。
it's a good sleep, sound sleep, and healing live concert.
ライブ後半にかけて盛り上がっていくので、ぜひ皆様も盛り上がってください！
We'll get more and more hyped toward the latter half, so please get hyped up too, everyone!
てな感じで、1曲目は『快眠!安眠!スヤリスト生活』を歌わせていただきました。
So, for the first song, I performed "Good sleep! Sound sleep! Suyarist life."
あの曲中のね、あの団長、踊りながら変身したシーンがありましたけど、
During that song, there was a scene where I transformed while dancing,
わかった？
did you notice?
わかった？っていうか、みんな気づいてる？
Did you notice? Or rather, is everyone aware?
っていうか、おメイクがちょっと変わりました！
Actually, my makeup has changed a bit!
お気づきでしょうか？
Did you notice?
まあ具体的にね、どういうところが変わったかと言いますと、
To be specific, as for what exactly has changed...
あの、髪の毛がですね、あの、サラサラによりなりました！
My hair has become even silkier!
ええ、サラサラになって、特に後ろとかね、わかるかな？ほら、サラサラ！
Yes, it's so silky. Especially from the back, can you tell? See, silky!
もう本当に、いつでもシャンプーのCM待ってます、
Really, I'm waiting for a shampoo commercial offer anytime!
てな感じでサラサラになったのと、あとおメイクもね、ちょっと変わっております。
That's how silky it's become, and my makeup has changed a bit too.
まあ、いろんな表情ができるようになったんですけど、
We can now make various facial expressions,
えーっと、なんか、なんか第3、ノエちゃんが怒るようなこと言ってみて。
like... hey staff, say something that would make me angry.
お、お。
Oh? Oh?
え、何？「おい、ちょっと太った？」
What's that? "Hey, did you gain a little weight?"
ん！何ぃ！
Hmph! What did you say?!
太ってないよ！最近ダイエット頑張ってるもん！
I didn't gain weight! I've been working hard on my diet lately!
てな感じで、前はちょっと結構ガチ怒りって感じだったんですけど、
Like that, before it looked like serious anger,
マイルド怒りになりました！はい。
but now it's a mild anger! Yes.
っていう感じで、あの、ちょっとね、いろんな表情ができるようになったので、それも踏まえて、
So, since I can now express various emotions, keeping that in mind,
あの、ライブ見てくれると嬉しいです。
I hope you enjoy watching the live show.
そして、ま、ノエちゃんも変わったんですけど、この変わったね、あの、お姿で、さらに、
And, while I have changed, with this updated appearance, additionally...
本日のステージはこちらです！
Today's stage is this one!
えー、すごいね、全景。
Wow, the full view looks amazing.
わあ！なんか本当に癒やしって感じだよね。もう本当に綺麗に、はい、作っていただきました。
Wow! It really feels so healing, doesn't it? They made it so beautifully for me.
ま、このね、周り。
And this surrounding area...
そう、周りね、これ雲？そう、雲の海みたいな感じで、ぷかぷか〜ってなっています。ええ。
Yes, around the stage, are these clouds? Yes, it's like a sea of clouds, floating gently. Yes.
そしてね、ま、こうやってね、雲の海から上もね、すごい！綺麗！
And looking up from this sea of clouds, wow, it's so beautiful!
なんか飾りが、ぐるぐるぐるぐる〜っと回っておりますので、
The decorations are spinning around and around,
いや、なんかね、あの、これからちょっとゲストパートとかもあるんですけど、
and we'll also have a guest segment coming up next,
なんかそれに合わせて、いろいろと変わってくみたいなので、ぜひ楽しみにしてみてくだい。
which will change in various ways to match, so please look forward to it.
それでは、次の曲、レッツゴー！
Now, onto the next song, let's go!
僕は今 夢旅の中
I am now in the middle of a dream journey.
あの星の島までも
Even to that island of stars...
飛んでゆける
...I can fly.
手のりウタうたう僕のユメクイ
My hand-sized singing Yumekui (Dream Eater)...
君のそばにも辿り着ける
...I can also reach your side.
最初に描いた
The dream I first drew...
夢を思い出せなくなったのは
...I wonder if the reason I can no longer remember it...
大人になったから？
...is because I've become an adult?
右か左かで
Torn between left and right,
いつまでも迷って
indecisive forever,
太陽が反転するまで
until the sun flipped,
しゃべりこんだ
we talked.
一つだけ
The single thing...
ポケットに入れてきたもの
...I brought along in my pocket:
おっきな
This big...
この愛をもって
...love in my hands.
僕は今
I am now...
夢旅の中
...in the middle of a dream journey.
あの星の
Even to that star's...
島までも飛んでゆける
...island, I can fly.
手のりウタうたう
My hand-sized singing...
僕のユメクイ
...Yumekui (Dream Eater).
君のそばにも
To your side,
辿り着ける
I can also reach.
カラフルな靄に
Stolen by a colorful mist,
心を奪われ
my heart was captivated,
ちょっとしたことに
and on some trivial things...
つまづいた保存
...I stumbled.
すりむいたところに
On my scraped skin...
君がくれたのは保存
...what you gave me was...
はずかしいくらいの
an embarrassingly...
可愛らしいばんそうこう
...cute adhesive bandage.
叶えるたびに
Every time I fulfill one,
食いつくすユメクイ
the Yumekui eats it up.
叶えるたびに
Every time I fulfill one,
また夢を見る
I dream a new dream again.
いくつになっても
No matter how old I get.
僕は今
I am now...
夢旅の中
...in the middle of a dream journey.
寄り道して保存
Taking a detour...
プレゼントを見つける
...and finding a present.
手のりウタうたう
My hand-sized singing...
僕のユメクイ
...Yumekui (Dream Eater).
描いた未来に
In the future I drew,
君がいつもいる
you are always there.
僕は今
I am now...
夢旅の中
...in the middle of a dream journey.
あの星の
Even to that star's...
島までも飛んでゆける
...island, I can fly.
手のりウタうたう
My hand-sized singing...
僕のユメクイ保存
...Yumekui (Dream Eater).
君のそばにも
To your side,
辿り着ける
I can also reach.
君のそばで
By your side,
ずっと夢を見る
I'll dream forever.
半端ない ぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっ ヘイ！
Unbelievable! Para-para-para-para-para, hey!
限界突破 ぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっ ヘイ！
Breaking limits! Para-para-para-para-para, hey!
毎日半端ない ぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっ ヘイ！
Every day is unbelievable! Para-para-para-para-para, hey!
限界突破 ぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっ ヘーイ！
Breaking limits! Para-para-para-para-para, hey!
最適温度 塞ぎきるゴースト
The perfect temperature, blocking out ghosts
八百万の 嫌な外的要素
The countless unpleasant external factors
何の気ないと 超あっけらかんと
Casually, with complete nonchalance
悪気もなく邪魔する毒親の誰かさんにバイバイバイ
toxic parents who interfere carelessly with absolutely no ill intent, bye-bye-bye!
自分時間だらくタイム確保
Securing my own personal lazy time
17時〜9時は死守マスト
Defending 5 PM to 9 AM is an absolute must
さらに愛や恋や甘いマイも忘れずに
And also don't forget love, romance, and sweet illusions
とどのつまり
In the end,
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって
Overworking is strictly off-limits,
注意喚起もしてますよ
So I'm issuing a warning!
ねえ楽して くまなくして 生きてくって難しいな だって
Living easily without dark circles under my eyes is so hard, because...
安定裏技は一夜漬け
My trusty fallback is cramming overnight,
甘い水に尾羽は広がる イヤー！
Spreading my wings in sweet water, yeah!
眠くなったら寝る
Sleeping when I get sleepy
お昼過ぎに起きる
Waking up past noon
遊びたくなったら遊ぶ
Playing when I want to play
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
Eating food when I get hungry
嬉しかったら笑う
Laughing when I'm happy
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
When I'm sad, it's fine to cry, isn't it?
明日の私のために今日も なんとか頑張るのさ
For the sake of tomorrow's me, I'll somehow do my best today
明日も頑張らなくていいように 頑張るのさ
Doing my best today, so I won't have to do my best tomorrow
怠惰じゃないこれ多分そうだ
This isn't laziness, I'm pretty sure of it
なんやでやることやっています
Somehow or another, I'm getting things done
WHAT? IF WHAT?
誰に知られなくたって別にいいから
Because I don't really care if anyone knows
私には私のマイルール
I have my own personal rules
明日楽するために はい、チーズ！
To make tomorrow easier, say cheese!
意外とこんな感じでラブアンドピースのある毎日を生きていたいのです
Surprisingly, I just want to live a life full of love and peace like this
Don't be shy... ドキドキしたい
Don't be shy, I want to feel my heart pounding
Let me shine... 明日天気になれ
Let me shine, may tomorrow be clear
To be excite... 心もっと踊りたい
To be excited, I want my heart to dance more
Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday Saturday
辛くなったら歌う
Singing when things get tough
むかついたら愚ちる
Venting when I get annoyed
やりたいようにやる
Doing whatever I want
それができたら苦労しないわ
If only it were that easy, I wouldn't be struggling
常に一喜一憂
Always swinging between joy and sorrow
してりゃ身が持たんから
Because if I do, I won't last
適当にセーブし ライフは回復
Saving appropriately to restore my life
で、まあ頑張るのさ
And, well, I'll do my best
適当にとまでは言うまいが まあ頑張るのさ
I won't tell you to just take it easy, but, well, I'll do my best
夢の中では...
In my dreams...
ずっとぐーたらしてやるんだ
I'll just laze around forever!
誰かのためとかそんなんじゃなく明日の私のために ファイト！
Not for anyone else, but for tomorrow's me... Fight!
楽するために苦しいことも乗り越えちゃうんだからね ファイト！
I'll even overcome the painful times to make things easier later... Fight!
やりたくないことやらないためにやりたくないことやれ ファイト！
To avoid doing what you don't want, do what you don't want to do... Fight!
あれ、これって結構頑張れてる私とっても偉いじゃないか ファイト！
Wait, I'm actually doing pretty well! Aren't I super amazing? Fight!
自分時間だらくタイム確保
Securing my own personal lazy time
17時〜9時は死守マスト
Defending 5 PM to 9 AM is an absolute must
さらに愛や恋や甘いマイも忘れずに とどのつまり
And also don't forget love, romance, and sweet illusions, in the end...
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって
Overworking is strictly off-limits,
注意喚起もしてますよ
So I'm issuing a warning!
ねえ楽して くまなくして 生きてくって難しいな だって
Living easily without dark circles under my eyes is so hard, because... quit it!
安定裏技は一夜漬け甘い水に尾羽は広がる イヤー！
My trusty fallback is cramming overnight, spreading my wings in sweet water, yeah!
眠くなったら寝る
Sleeping when I get sleepy
お昼過ぎに起きる
Waking up past noon
遊びたくなったら遊ぶ
Playing when I want to play
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
Eating food when I get hungry
嬉しかったら笑う
Laughing when I'm happy
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
When I'm sad, it's fine to cry, isn't it?
明日の私のために今日も なんとか頑張るのさ
For the sake of tomorrow's me, I'll somehow do my best today
明日も頑張らなくていいように 頑張るのさ
Doing my best today, so I won't have to do my best tomorrow
半端ない ぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっ ヘイ！
Unbelievable! Para-para-para-para-para, hey!
限界突破 ぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっ ヘイ！
Breaking limits! Para-para-para-para-para, hey!
毎日半端ない ぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっ ヘイ！
Every day is unbelievable! Para-para-para-para-para, hey!
限界突破 ぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっ ヘーイ！
Breaking limits! Para-para-para-para-para, hey!
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, invent something
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, invent something
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
Cancel your live bookings and invent something
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I am going to become that kind of invention king
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, invent something
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, invent something
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
Cancel your live bookings and invent something
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I am going to become that kind of invention king
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン 自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン 自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
幼少期の頃から 家で聴いてた音楽は ハウスミュージック
Since I was a child, the music I listened to at home was house music
サブスクのプレイリスト開いて 曲ディグったなら クラブで DJ
Opening up subscription playlists, once I dig up tracks, DJ at the club
パソコン開いたなら DTM ソフトは Ableton Live
Opening up my computer for DTM, the software is Ableton Live
だけど今作りたいのは
But what I want to make now...
蓄音機
...is a gramophone.
サークルでの宴会芸
Party tricks in a club,
ノリで始めたバンドで
with a band started on a whim,
まぐれでバズってメジャーデビュー
we buzzed by fluke and made our major debut.
なぜか今はしがないミュージシャン
For some reason, we're just lowly musicians now.
踊るエジソン自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem.
歌うエジソンジソン心
Singing Edison, self-respect.
踊るエジソン自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem.
歌うエジソンジソン心
Singing Edison, self-respect.
YouTubeも見（て）得る 1%のひらめき
Inspiration from 1% of the ideas from watching YouTube,
インスピレーション
inspiration.
SNS通して繋がる 発明家の
Connected through social media, inventors'
コミュニケーション
communication.
インスタ映え狙った投稿
Posts aimed at being Instagrammable,
webニュースで情報収集
gathering information through web news.
間違いなくこれからの時代来るのは
Without a doubt, what's coming in the future...
活動写真
...is motion pictures.
いや、絶対来ると思うんだけどなー
No, I really think it's coming, though...
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, invent!
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, invent!
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
Kick away live bookings and invent!
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I will become such an inventor king!
踊るエジソン自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem.
歌うエジソンジソン心
Singing Edison, self-respect.
踊るエジソン自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem.
歌うエジソンジソン心
Singing Edison, self-respect.
今日もこのまま さよならじゃないよ
Like this today, it's not goodbye,
手をとってくれたなら
if you take my hand.
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に 君を連れていくよ
In a night where even secrets fall into slumber, I will take you with me.
それは例えば 遠く離れていたって
It's for example, even if we were far apart,
手をつないでいられるような 奇跡のような
like we could hold hands, like a miracle...
話をしよう
Let's talk,
窓は開けておいて
leave the window open.
今日までを思い出して
Thinking back to today,
一つ一つ並べたら
if we lined them up one by one,
明日の雨が気になりだして
I start to worry about tomorrow's rain,
どうも眠れないみたいだ
seems like I can't sleep at all.
変わりたくないことや
Things I don't want to change,
変わらなきゃいけないことも
and things I have to change,
少し忘れたまま
while forgetting them a little,
窓の外を眺めていたんだ
I was gazing out the window.
あぁ
Ah...
雨が降り出すその前に
Before the rain starts to fall,
君のところまで 行けるような気がして
I felt like I could reach where you are.
目を閉じてみたんだ
I tried closing my eyes,
そしてこのまま 遠くへといこうSafe
and just like this, let's go far away.
手をとってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll take my hand.
秘密も眠りにつくような夜を
In a night where even secrets fall into slumber,
君と泳いでいくよ
I will swim with you.
街の明かりが消えるたびに笑って
Every time the city lights go out, we laugh,
路地裏で抱き合おう
let's embrace in the back alley.
馬鹿みたいな
Let's tell stories like idiots,
話をしよう
let's talk,
窓は開けておいて
leave the window open.
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
愛おしいことや
Beloved things,
無せないものを
and things I cannot lose...
教えてくれたのは
What taught me that,
今日みたいな
was like today.
夜を重ねて
Layering the nights,
また一つ重なっていくから...
Again, one by one they pile up...
目を閉じてみたんだ
I tried closing my eyes.
今夜　私たちだけで眠ろう
Tonight, let's sleep just the two of us.
誰にも言わないで
Don't tell anyone.
君が眠りにつくその少し前に
Just a little before you fall asleep...
名前を呼んで
...call my name.
叶わない願いに胸は痛んで
My heart aches with wishes that won't come true,
俯いてしまうけど
and I hang my head, but...
誰もいない街へ誘いに行くから
since I'll invite you to a town where no one is there.
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ
It's not a goodbye for today.
手をとってくれたなら
If you take my hand,
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に
on a night where even secrets fall asleep,
君を連れていくよ
I will take you with me.
それは例えば遠く離れてたって
Even if we are far apart, for example,
手を繋いでいられるような
like being able to hold hands,
奇跡のような
in a miracle-like way,
話をしよう
let's talk.
窓は開けといて
Keep the window open.
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
愛しいことや失くせないものを
What teaches me about precious things and things I can't lose...
教えてくれたのは今日みたいな<,s:
...is nights like today...
夜を重ねて織り上げてきた
...that we have lived through and woven together.
私たちに響く音
The sound that resonates in us...
響く言葉
...the resonating words.
はーい！
Hi!
ということで、皆さん、今回のライブ、なんと、新衣装が、ぽぽぽぽぽぽぽ、ありましたー！
And so, everyone! For this concert, there's actually a new outfit... ta-da! Here it is!
ということで、あの、びっくりしたかな？びっくりしたんじゃないかなと思います！
So, um, were you surprised? I bet you were really surprised!
あの、こちらね、すごい、あの、きらびやかな衣装となっているんですけど...
Um, this outfit is really, um, gorgeous and sparkling, but...
ちょっと今スクショ、どう、撮る？
Why don't we take some screenshots now?
えい！可愛いですか？
Hyah! Is it cute?
ぜひ、あの、ハッシュタグでね、あの、ぜひ呟いてください！
Please, um, post about it using the hashtag!
可愛いでしょう！
It's cute, right?
何やらね、この後、ちょっと衣装のね、色々、あの、細部まで、ちょっと見る機会がありそうな予感がするので...
It feels like I might have a chance to show you the details of this outfit later...
一旦ね、スクショだけ。お願いします！
So for now, just the screenshots. Please!
そして、あとこちらね、
Also, this one...
見て！手首に、ぷらぷらって紐があるんだけど、これね、取れます！
Look! There are dangling strings on my wrists, but these can be removed!
じゃあ、と、とってもらおうかな？
So, could you remove them for me?
えい！えい！
Hyah! Hyah!
ということで、はい、取れまーす！
So yes, they can be removed!
こちらバージョンも、スクショ、撮ってもらおう！
Let's take screenshots of this version too!
えい！可愛いですか？
Hyah! Is it cute?
やぁ！
Yah!
ね、すごい、可愛らしい衣装。
See, it's a really lovely outfit.
え、ちょっとね、あの、ドキドキするんですが、
Um, I'm feeling a bit nervous,
ふふ、いや、なんか、
haha, but somehow,
でもちょっと一人、寂しいな。なんか、団員さん...
I feel a bit lonely on my own. I wish the Order Members were here...
あ！あれ可愛いね！お、なんか、モゾモゾしてる。お、どうした？どうした？
Ah! That is cute! Oh, it's wriggling. Oh, what's wrong? What's wrong?
きゃー！
Kyaa!
団員さん飛んできた！そんなに、え、ノエルちゃんに会いたかったんかな？可愛いね！
An Order Member flew over! Did you really want to see Noel-chan that much? So cute!
いっぱいスクショ撮れた？
Did you get to take lots of screenshots?
うーん、団員さんとのツーショット！
Mmm, a two-shot with an Order Member!
可愛い。え、何々？
So cute. Eh, what's that?
あ、今日は安眠テーマで、あ、心地よい、あ、なるほどね。ん？
Ah, today's theme is peaceful sleep, so it's comfortable... Ah, I see. Hm?
ここのリクエスト？
A request here?
あ、子守唄みたいな曲が聴きたい？あ、そうなの？団員さん。
Ah, you want to hear a lullaby-like song? Oh, really, Order Member?
じゃあ、せっかくね、団員さん来てくれたし、一緒に、じゃあ、子守唄、
Well, since you've come all this way, let's do a lullaby together...
うん、の、歌う、歌う！なんか、ちょっとついてきて！
Yeah, I'll sing, I'll sing! Come along with me!
一緒に行くよー！おらおらーい！
Let's go together! Alrighty!
小さな人の子よ
Little child of man,
森へ迷い込んだ
who has wandered into the forest,
大きな...
big...
大きな羽が
Your big wings,
ぼうやは見えないのね
boy, you cannot see them, can you?
なにも知らない
Knowing nothing,
まあるいほっぺよ
your round little cheeks.
ねむれや
Sleep now,
ねむれ
sleep.
しずかな
To the quiet
水辺においで
waterside, come.
ぼうやの夢は
The little boy's dream,
竜の背に運ばれて
is carried on a dragon's back,
山の向こうへ消える
and disappears beyond the mountains.
よろずの子も
All the children,
ならんでねむる
sleep lined up side-by-side.
七つ数えたら
Once you count to seven,
仲良くねむってゆく
they sleep peacefully together.
なにも見えない
Seeing nothing,
小さな おめめよ
those tiny little eyes.
ねむれや
Sleep now,
ねむれ
sleep.
そよぐ草むらおいで
To the swaying grass, come.
ぼうやの夢は
The little boy's dream,
母さんを探しては
searches for his mother,
空の向こうへ帰る
and returns beyond the sky.
竜の背に運ばれて
Carried on a dragon's back,
山の向こうへ消える
and disappears beyond the mountains.
プラネタリウム
[Title: Planetarium]
夕月夜 顔だす 消えてく 子供の声
The evening moon peeks out, the voices of children fade away.
遠く遠く
Far away, far away,
この空のどこかに
somewhere in this sky,
君はいるんだろう
I wonder if you are there.
夏の終わりに2人で抜け出した
At the end of summer, we snuck out together,
この公園で見つけた
and in this park, we found
あの星座 何だか 覚えてる?
that constellation... do you somehow remember it?
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I trace my memories,
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
I want to see the same happiness.
あの香りとともに
Together with that scent,
花火がぱっと開く
fireworks suddenly burst open.
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are,
今すぐ かけだして 行きたいよ
I want to run and go right now.
まっ暗で何も 見えない
It's pitch black and I can't see anything,
怖くても大丈夫
but it's okay even if it's scary.
数えきれない星空が
The countless starry sky,
今もずっと ここにあるんだよ
is still, forever, here right now.
泣かないよ 昔君と見た きれいな空だったから
I won't cry, because it was a beautiful sky I saw with you long ago
あの道まで 響く靴の音が耳に残る
Along that road, the echoing sound of shoes remains in my ears
大きな自分の影を見つめて 想うのでしょう
Staring at my own large shadow, I wonder what I'm thinking
ちっとも変わらないはずなのに
Even though it shouldn't have changed at all
せつない気持ちふくらんでく
These painful feelings keep swelling up
どんなに想ったって 君はもういない
No matter how much I miss you, you're already gone
行きたいよ 君のそばに 小さくても小さくても
I want to go to your side, even if it's small, even if it's small
1番に君が好きだよ 強くいられる
I love you the most, I can be strong
願いを流れ星に そっと唱えてみたけれど
I whispered a wish to a shooting star, but...
泣かないよ 届くだろう きれいな空に
I won't cry, it will reach that beautiful sky
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I'll trace my memories
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
I want to see the same happiness
あの香りとともに 花火がぱっと開く
Along with that scent, fireworks burst open
行きたいよ 君のところへ 小さな手をにぎりしめて
I want to go to you, clutching our small hands
泣きたいよ それはそれは きれいな空だった
I want to cry, it was, oh it was, a beautiful sky
願いを流れ星に そっと唱えてみたけれど
I whispered a wish to a shooting star, but...
泣きたいよ 届かない想いをこの空に...
I want to cry, my unreachable feelings into this sky...
[曲：RELAY / 作詞：カトウチヒロ / 作曲：Konami Amusement]
[Song: RELAY / Lyrics: Chihiro Kato / Composition: Konami Amusement]
もっ何十回 もう何百回も 震えるソラ見上げて
Dozens of times, hundreds of times, looking up at the trembling sky
辿り着いた場所が 運命のダイヤモンド
The place we arrived at is the diamond of destiny
何千回 もう何万回も 涙流したきみへ
To you who shed tears thousands, tens of thousands of times
ねえ 諦められたことはあったっけ？
Tell me, was there ever anything we could just give up on?
「憧れ＝限界」だから もういらないよ
Because "aspiration = limit", I don't need it anymore
そこにとどまるなんて もったいないでしょ
Just staying there is such a waste, right?
それぞれの物語 交差する瞬間を 見つめる意味は
The meaning of watching the moment our respective stories intersect is...
放った夢だけ 大きな弧を描いて
Only the dreams we let go of draw a big arc
はちきれそうな煌めきを
Carrying a sparkle that's about to burst
消えることなく どこまででも
Without fading away, wherever it may go
世界の向こうに
To the other side of the world...
届けよう
...let's deliver it!
終わることのない
Never-ending...
この胸 of 衝動は
...this impulse in my heart...
どうしたって
...no matter what...
どうしても
...no matter how...
ぼくを呼んでいた
...was calling out to me.
だから
That's why...
その先へと
...to the future beyond...
走り続ける
...I will keep running.
次へ 次へ
To the next, to the next!
妄想だった 中途半端な
It was just a delusion, a half-hearted...
ふがいなさ 抱えて
...helplessness that I carried...
立ち尽くしていた 通り雨
...as I stood frozen in the rain.
通り雨はプレリュード
The passing rain is a prelude.
何千回も 何万回も
Thousands of times, tens of thousands of times...
挑み続けた きみへ
...to you, who kept on challenging.
ねえ 聴かせてよ「夢は叶うんだ」って
Hey, let me hear you say, "dreams do come true!"
「諦め＝完敗」ならば 絶対にないよ
If "giving up = complete defeat," then that's absolutely not happening.
だれに邪魔されようと
No matter who tries to get in our way...
ためらわないで
...don't hesitate!
託された情熱を
The passion entrusted to us...
落とさずに つないでく
...we will pass it on without letting it drop.
そう 最後まで
Yes, until the very end!
フラグに誓い
Swearing on the flag...
雄々しく はためいて
...letting it flutter bravely...
鳴り止まない ファンファーレ
...an endless fanfare...
いつも心に
...was always...
流れていた
...flowing in my heart.
遠い未来へ 祈るよう
As if praying to a distant future...
忘れられない
...I cannot forget...
あの日々の後悔を
...the regrets of those days.
追いかけて 追いかけて
Chasing after them, chasing after them...
滑り込んだ
...I slipped into...
この想い
...these feelings.
青いソラに
Into the blue sky...
ふと 溢れていった
...they suddenly overflowed...
遠く 遠く
...far, far away.
終わらない 終わらない
It's never-ending, never-ending!
仕事が山積み 終わらない
A mountain of work, it's never-ending!
止まらない 止まらない
It's unstoppable, unstoppable!
それでも時間は 止まらない
But still, time won't stop!
YO! YO!
ヘッド ヘット
Weary, exhausted,
溜まり溜まった ヘント
with so much pent-up resentment.
天罰 唱えろ バット
Invoke divine punishment, bat!
コンボ 滅する 金属バット
Destructive combo with a metal bat!
Swing!
今日もてんこ盛り
Today is packed full too,
today is packed full too!
Wah!
No more 無知
No more ignorance!
ギミギミ じゅし
Gimme, gimme juicy!
I see
奔走 Anytime 奔走 Anytime
Running around anytime, running around anytime!
はぁーあ
*Sigh*
骨抜き ぶれすで
Weak-kneed breath...
N3 すからぱん
N3, empty-pocketed...
わっしょい
Wasshoi!
自分自身に 厳しすぎちゃう
Too hard on myself,
すぐさま ヘラヘラ 優等生
instantly smiling, the honor student,
さっぱり足らない 順応性
with absolutely no adaptability.
自分自身としっかり 向き合う
Facing myself properly,
一番 必要なものは トレビアン
the most necessary thing is très bien.
ご褒美を頂戴
Give me a reward!
Wah!
てんてこ舞うような リズムに
To this frantically dancing rhythm...
バイバイしちゃえ
...say bye-bye!
どれにファンの 音に ごらん
Look at whichever fan sound it is,
Yeah!
ギュウギュウ詰めじゃ ダメ どんどんフリーダム
No crowding, let's get more and more freedom!
Uh... Uh...
オーライ オーライ
All right, all right!
好きなもの食べ放題
All-you-can-eat of whatever you like,
お気召すまま気の向くままに
as you please, whenever you feel like it.
ほらもっともっと頂戴
Look, give me more and more!
膨大
Enormous!
Get ready!
タボタボです
It's baggy,
たまにカラフル
sometimes colorful,
満ち足りた
satisfied,
いっそ 胸張り大盛り
let's be proud and have a large serving!
要らない
No need!
まやかしの甘やかし
Deceptive pampering,
ハッピーになるため歌おう
let's sing to be happy!
声高らかに
Loud and clear!
Yay!
自分自身がやっぱり一番
As I thought, I myself am number one!
理性と欲望が平行線
Reason and desire are parallel lines,
望みは幸せエンドレス
wishing for endless happiness.
自分自身としっかり付き合う
Dealing with myself properly,
我慢は体に毒だよ トレビアン
patience is poison to the body, très bien.
ご褒美を頂戴
Give me a reward!
Wah!
てんてこ舞うような リズムに
To this frantically dancing rhythm...
バイバイしちゃえ
...say bye-bye!
どれにファンの 音に ごらん
Look at whichever fan sound it is,
Yeah!
ギュウギュウ詰めじゃ ダメ どんどんフリーダム
No crowding, let's get more and more freedom!
1 2 の 3 はい！
1, 2, 3, go!
窮屈な 窮屈に
In this cramped, cramped...
疲弊やす トレス
...exhausting stress...
状態条件から 解放しちゃえ
...let's release ourselves from these conditional states!
もっともっともっともっと まだまだ足りない
More, more, more, more, still not enough!
本日は欲望解放パーティーナイト
Today is the party night to unleash your desires!
乾杯！
Cheers!
トレビアン ご褒美 頂戴
Très bien! Give me my reward!
てんてこ舞うようなリズムにバイバイしちゃえ
Say bye-bye to this hectic rhythm!
トレビアン 脳裏に ご来光
Très bien! Sunrise in my mind!
きゅーきゅーと詰めちゃえどんどんフリーダム
Squeeze it tight, more and more freedom!
ぎゅーぎゅー詰めのこの褒美 どんどん 好きになる
I'm falling in love with this tightly packed reward more and more!
フィーバー！
Fever!
輝夜の城で踊りたい
[Song: I Want to Dance in Kaguya's Castle]
おいで！おいで！誘惑のDance again
Come on! Come on! Temptation, Dance again
おいでよおいで！輝夜の城へ
Come on, come on! To Kaguya's castle
出逢いがあやつるミステリー
The mystery that meetings manipulate
危険なペルソナ
A dangerous persona
助けて〜！
Help me~!
踊ろう！踊ろう！終わらないDance beat
Let's dance! Let's dance! Never-ending Dance beat
踊ろうよ踊ろう！輝夜の城で
Let's dance, let's dance! In Kaguya's castle
夜空を切りとるレーザービーム
Laser beams that cut through the night sky
私と見てよ？
Watch with me?
にゃー？
Nyaa?
まばゆい星が照らす想い
The feelings that the dazzling stars illuminate
今宵の夢よ永遠に
Tonight's dream is eternal
明日のことは忘れたいの
I want to forget about tomorrow
ペコ〜！
Peko~!
私は紅い薔薇の姫よ
I am the Crimson Rose Princess
優しくさらわれたい
I want to be kidnapped gently
そっと囁いて 意味ありげに目をそらす
Whisper softly and look away suggestively
あなたは白い月の騎士
You are the White Moon Knight
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hands that touched are still hot
のがさずに抱きしめて
Don't let go, hold me tight
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
Call this miracle love, won't you?
おいで！おいで！情熱でDance again
Come on! Come on! With passion, Dance again
おいでよおいで！輝夜の城へ
Come on, come on! To Kaguya's castle
迷いを飲みこむエナジー
The energy that swallows hesitation
眠らぬパッショネイト
Sleepless, passionate
でしょ？
Right?
踊ろう！踊ろう！止まらないDance beat
Let's dance! Let's dance! Unstoppable Dance beat
踊ろうよ踊ろう！輝夜の城で
Let's dance, let's dance! In Kaguya's castle
星座が織りなすディスコティーク
Discotheque woven by the constellations
私も混ぜて？
Include me too?
ノエッ〜！
Noe~!
きらめく星に誓う心
Hearts swearing to the shimmering stars
儚い夢でいいわ
A fleeting dream is fine
明日は明日の風が吹くの
Tomorrow, tomorrow's wind will blow
だよねっ！
That's right!
私は黒い薔薇の姫よ
I am the Black Rose Princess
激しくさらわれたい
I want to be kidnapped intensely
だから微笑んで追いかけてと目が誘う
So smile, my eyes invite you to chase me
あなたも黒い月の騎士
You are also the Black Moon Knight
瞳の奥は熱い
The depths of your eyes are hot
つかまえて抱きしめて
Catch me, hold me tight
この奇跡は恋を呼ぶのね
Call this miracle love, won't you?
一緒に行こう！
Let's go together!
ついてきてよ
Follow me!
他の人を見ちゃ嫌...
Don't look at anyone else...
私だけを見て！
Look only at me!
後悔するわよ
You'll regret it!
楽しもっ！
Let's have fun!
早くしなさいよ
Hurry up!
鈍いのですね...
You're quite dense...
いいの？
Is that okay?
私は紅い薔薇の姫よ
I am the Crimson Rose Princess
優しくさらわれたい
I want to be kidnapped gently
そっと囁いて 意味ありげに目をそらす
Whisper softly and look away suggestively
あなたは白い月の騎士
You are the White Moon Knight
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hands that touched are still hot
のがさずに抱きしめて
Don't let go, hold me tight
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
Call this miracle love, won't you?
はーい！
Hi everyone!
ということで、3期生のみんなと「輝夜の城で踊りたい」を歌って踊りましたー！
And with that, I sang and danced to 'Kaguya no Shiro de Odoritai' with all of Gen 3!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ノエちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうー！
Noe-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ちょっと可愛いんじゃない？
Isn't that a bit too cute?
動きがちょっと...
Your movements are a bit...
ちょっとお茶目な感じで、はい、どうですか、可愛いですか？
With a bit of a playful feel. Yes, how is it? Is it cute?
可愛いー！
So cute!
すごいね、なんかここがめっちゃすごいです。
Amazing! Somehow, this part is really amazing...
おっぱいがお尻だよ、ノエちゃん！
Your breasts are like a butt, Noe-chan!
こんなおっぱいに挨拶しちゃう。
I'd greet breasts like these.
でも、今日からはさ、こう話せばいいのかな？
But starting today, should I talk like this?
違う違う！ おかしいおかしい！
No, no! That's weird!
えーっと、今回の衣装はね、あの200万人の記念で、はい、作っていただきました！
Well, this outfit was made to commemorate reaching 2 million subscribers!
他にも変わったところ、今日のライブであるんだけど...
There are other changes in today's live show, too...
ノエちゃん、あれ？メイクが変わってる？
Noe-chan, wait. Did your makeup change?
あ！気づいたー！？
Ah! You noticed!?
気づいた？ということで、そうなんですよ、ちょっとメイク変わりました。どうですか？
You noticed? That's right, my makeup changed a bit. How is it?
全然違う！可愛いー！
It's totally different! So cute!
ちなみに、お気に入りの顔がありまして、ちょっと、あの、お困り顔がね、可愛いでしょ？
By the way, I have a favorite expression. My 'troubled face' is cute, right?
お口が、こう、ぷっくりなってるんです。こだわりだね。
My mouth gets all pouty like this. - That's a nice detail.
うわー！
Whoa!
じゃあちょっと、衣装せっかくなんで、下からちょっと舐めるように...
So since we have this outfit, let's take a look from the bottom up...
いきましょう、お靴から見ましょう、お靴から。
Let's go, let's look from the shoes first.
あら可愛いお靴！よく見せて。ヒールなんだね！<
Oh, what cute shoes! Show us closer. Oh, they have heels!
普段はね、通常でぺったんこだから、ちょっと身長盛りました。
Usually they're flat shoes, so I boosted my height a little.
リボンが後ろに！え、可愛い！ - そうなんです、ついてます。
There are ribbons in the back! Oh, cute! - That's right, they're there.
じゃあちょっと、舐めるように... おおー！うわー！
Then, sweeping up... Ooh! Whoa!
いったいどんなおパンツ... こら！変態おじさん！
What kind of panties... - Hey! Pervert!
こんな感じで... ちょっとさささっと終わらないで！まだ舐めてる最中だから！
Like this... - Wait, don't rush through! We're still sweeping up!
おおー！すごい！
Ooh! Amazing!
ここね、ここが開いてて... ノエちゃん、ここ、ご覧ください！
Here, this part is open... - Noe-chan, look at this!
ここの、この、この、この胸の、ここの隙間、隙間、隙間！
This, this, this, this chest, this gap, gap, gap!
わかります？この、ちちとちちの間の隙間！本当だ、すごいね。
Do you see? The gap between boob and boob! - True, it's amazing.
隙間がね、ほら！大丈夫ですかこれ？
The gap, look! Is this okay?
大丈夫、大丈夫！最高のお衣装になってます。
It's fine, it's fine! It's the ultimate outfit.
じゃあちょっと、上を見せるにあたって、このヒラヒラ取れるから、ちょっと取ってもいい？ - え、可愛い、取ってみて！
To show the upper part, this fluttery part can be removed, can I take it off? - Oh, cute, try taking it off!
取ってください！ おおー！見やすい！
Please take it off! Ooh! Much easier to see!
万歳！ 横はどうなってるの？ゆっくりくるくる回って。
Banzai! - How does the side look? Spin around slowly.
可愛いー！髪の毛ふわふわで可愛い！
Cute! Her hair is so fluffy and cute!
髪型もめちゃくちゃ凝ってて... ハーフツイン？ リボンが髪に巻き込んである感じで。
The hairstyle is also super elaborate... - Half-twin tails? It looks like ribbons are woven into her hair.
そう、編み込んで。姫騎士なんでね、お姫様みたいになってます。
Yes, braided in. Since I'm a Princess Knight, it looks like a princess.
お姫様になってます。ノエちゃん、可愛い！
It looks like a princess. - Noe-chan, you're cute!
可愛すぎる！こんなの好きになっちゃう。ちょっと、カエル化したいからいつもの動きして。
Too cute! I'm falling in love. Wait, I want to get turned off, so do your usual movement.
待って、待って、ちょっと好きじゃなくなってきた...
Wait, wait, I'm starting to like you less...
危ない、危ない、恋するところだった。
Close one, close one, I almost fell in love.
いやでも、本当に可愛い衣装、ありがとうございました。おめでとう！
But really, thank you so much for the cute outfit. - Congratulations!
いやでもさ、みんなさ、今回は団長の新衣装お披露目だったから、みんなにはちょっとアイドル衣装だったんですけど、
But you know, this time was Danchou's new outfit reveal, so everyone else wore their idol outfits,
みんなも衣装持ってるじゃん？だから、並んだりとかも今後したいな！ 絶対やろう！並ぼう並ぼう！
But you all have your outfits too, right? So I'd love to line up together like that in the future! - Definitely! Let's line up!
それで、また歌って踊りたいな！ え、それやりたい！絶対やろう！
And then, I want to sing and dance again! - Oh, I want to do that! Let's definitely do it!
あるのかなー？ はい！
I wonder if there is...? - Yes!
ということで、ここから大事なお知らせをたくさんしていきます！ お願いします！
So, from here we have lots of important announcements! - Please do!
まず、ホロライブ3期生の単独ライブ！「hololive 3rd Generation Live #きゅるるん3期生大作戦 最強アイドル、推しかないでしょ！」開催決定しております！
First, Hololive 3rd Gen's solo live! 'hololive 3rd Generation Live #KyururunGen3GreatOperation: Ultimate Idols, You Have No Choice But To Stan!' has been officially announced!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、日時ですが、2026年1月17日と18日の2日間にわたって開催されます！
Yes! The dates are January 17th and 18th, 2026, held over two days!
会場はね、あのデカい！Kアリーナ横浜となってます！ おおー！すごい！
The venue is that massive K-Arena Yokohama! - Ooh! Amazing!
昨日ね、なんと、二次先行が終わったところなんですけど、
Yesterday, the second pre-order ticket sales just ended, but...
なんかね、この後、先着の一般販売が、12月14日の、お昼の12時に...
But after this, the general first-come-first-served ticket sales will start on December 14th at 12:00 PM...
...みたいなので、ちょっとね...
...so, you know...
まだまだ諦めずにね、チャンスね。
Don't give up yet, there's still a chance.
大変だと思うけど、ぜひぜひ、あの、勝ち取ってください！
It might be tough, but please, please, win it!
お願いします！
Please!
そして配信チケットはね、まだありますので、絶賛発売中ですので、よろしくお願いいたします！
And stream tickets are still available, they are on sale now, so please check them out!
お願いします！
Please!
そして、まあ、このライブを見てくださった方で、まあ、買い忘れてる人はいないと思うけど...
And also, for those who watched this live, I don't think anyone forgot to buy it, but...
あの、グッズのね、先行販売と受注販売も、明日のね、えー、11月25日の18時までとなっております。
the pre-sale and made-to-order sale of the merchandise is until tomorrow, November 25th at 18:00.
マリン：明日ね！
ノエル：そう！
Marine: Tomorrow, right!
Noel: Yes!
だから、あの、ライブ会場でペンライト振りたいとか、配信見ながらペンライト振りたいよって人はぜひ、えー、この機会をお見逃しなく！
So, if you want to wave a penlight at the venue, or while watching the stream, please don't miss this opportunity!
現地行く人はぜひとも、絶対絶対あったほうが盛り上がりますよ！
For those going to the venue, having one will definitely make it more exciting!
お願いします！
Please!
いや、楽しみだね！
Man, I'm looking forward to it!
めっちゃ楽しみ！
So looking forward to it!
そう、団長もね、ちょっとおメイクを変えたから...
Yes, Dancho also changed her makeup a bit...
あー、そう、撮るのも楽しみー
Ah, yes, looking forward to seeing it!
そんな感じで、せっ、せっかくね、来てくれたから、意気込みを一言ちょっと、聞こうかなと。
So, since you're all here, how about a quick word on your enthusiasm?
一言ね！
Just one word!
ノエル：爆する？誰から行くの？
マリン：爆する？
Noel: Are we doing something crazy? Who's going first?
Marine: Crazy?
ぺこら：じゃあ、マリンからこういう順番で。
フレア：マリンからね。
Pekora: Then, starting from Marine in this order.
Flare: From Marine, right.
マリン、すごい良いこと言ってくれるんだろうな。
Marine is probably going to say something really nice.
がんばるぞ！
I'll do my best!
おいおいおい！
Hey, hey, hey!
楽しむぞ！
Let's have fun!
おお、一言ね。
Oh, just a word.
みんなで盛り上げるぞ！
Let's liven it up together!
あ、ありがとう！え、え、何々？あ、あれ？
Ah, thank you! Huh, what's this? Oh?
あ、光の速さで去っていった！
Ah, they left at the speed of light!
みんな、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you!
てな感じで、えー、ここからは、ノエルちゃんの告知に行きます！
With that, from here on, we'll move to Noel's announcements!
えー、まず一つ目は、こちら！
First, here's the first one!
はい！今年も出ます！白銀ノエル誕生日記念2025のグッズ、わーい！
Yes! It's coming out this year too! Shirogane Noel Birthday Commemoration 2025 merchandise, yay!
えー、生誕グッズ、まずは、こちら！
Birthday merch, first, here's this one!
はい！えー、嘘の世界へ！キラキラLEDアートパネル。えー、イラストは、MyungYi先生が、はい、描いてくれました。ありがとうございます！
Yes! "To the World of Lies! Glittering LED Art Panel". The illustration was drawn by MyungYi-sensei. Thank you very much!
いつもお世話になってます。ラブチラブチ！
Thank you as always for your support. Love you, love you!
今回のね、生誕ライブのステージと新衣装が、えー、テーマになっております。
The stage and new costume from this birthday live are the theme.
ま、LEDということで、こちら光る、ということでね、
Since it's LED, it glows, so...
あのぜひお部屋に飾って、あの今回のライブを思い出して、そう、思い出にしてください！
please display it in your room and remember this live, yes, make it a wonderful memory!
はい！そして次は、こちら！
Yes! And next, here is this!
はい！色んなノエルちゃん♡ランダムマルチバンド、ということで、まるえり先生が描いてくれました。ありがとうございます！
Yes! "Various Noel-chan Random Multi-band"! It was drawn by Marueri-sensei. Thank you very much!
いや、色んなね、ノエルちゃんがいますので、
There are various Noels, so...
ま、ちょっと、どのノエルちゃんがおうちに来るかな？ってちょっと楽しみにしつつ、届いたらね、
please look forward to seeing which Noel comes to your home, and once it arrives,
ま、マルチバンド、こちら、あの、お片付けの必需品となってます。
this multi-band is a must-have for tidying up.
え、ノエルちゃんも使っておりますので、あの、ぜひね、コードまとめるときとか、
Noel also uses it, so please use it to tie up cords,
はい、実用性に富んでますので、使ってみてください！
as it's highly practical!
次は、えー、こちら！
Next, here is this!
はい！えー、姫騎士ノエルぬいぐるみキーホルダー、ということで、
Yes! "Princess Knight Noel Plushie Keyring"!
えー、昨年はね、あの、サンタさんのノエルちゃんがぬいぐるみとして、はい、キーホルダーで出たんですが、
Last year, Santa Noel was released as a plushie keyring,
今回は、せっかく新衣装が出了たので、えー、こちらでぬいぐるみキーホルダーを、えー、作りました！
but since we got a new costume this time, we made a plushie keyring of this one!
あの、姫騎士として団員さんを守りますので、ぜひ肌身離さず、えー、持っててください！
I will protect my fans as a princess knight, so please keep it close to you at all times!
えー、次は、こちら！
Next, here is this!
はい！えー、わんちょむ2wayネックピロー、ということで、
Yes! "Wanchomu 2-Way Neck Pillow"!
ま、安眠にね、最適なネックピローなんですけど、今回は、なんとひっくり返すとわんちょむになっている、ということで、
It's a neck pillow perfect for a good night's sleep, but this time, if you turn it inside out, it becomes Wanchomu!
ま、わんちょむはね、あの今年から団長のおうちにお迎えしたわんちゃんのことなんですけど、
Wanchomu is the dog that I welcomed into my home this year,
えー、グッズにしちゃいました！えっちょっとね、あの、ノエルちゃんの、はい、あの、私情が入ってます、
and I turned him into merch! A bit of Noel's personal bias is in here,
ということで、ぜひ団員さんのおうちにもお迎えしてくだ...さい！
so please welcome him into your homes too!
えー、最後にフルセットを見てみましょう！こちら！
Finally, let's take a look at the full set! Here it is!
はい！今年もいっぱい、いっぱいグッズが出ました！いや、ぜひぜひ、あの、ゲットしてみてね。
Yes! So many items came out this year too! Please be sure to get them.
そして、このね、全部のフルセット特典があります。それはこちら！
And there is a bonus for purchasing the full set. Here it is!
はい！ということで、フルセットを購入してくださった方に、チェキ風ブロマイドカード付いてきます！
Yes! So, for those who purchase the full set, you'll get a polaroid-style bromide card!
やったー！とても素敵。ま、イラストはね、MyungYi先生のイラストで、
Yay! It's so lovely. The illustration is by MyungYi-sensei,
こちらに、えーと、あの通常バージョンは箔押しの複製サインが、はい、あの、ペタってなるんですけど、
and the regular version will have a foil-stamped printed signature,
えー、数量限定バージョンは、団長の直筆サインが付いてきます。
but the limited edition version comes with my actual handwritten signature!
あの、心を込めて書きますので、ぜひゲットしてみてください。
I will sign each one with love, so please try to get it.
さらにね、さらにさらに、フルセットを購入してくれた方全員に、特典ボイスも付いてきちゃいます！
On top of that, everyone who purchases the full set will also receive a special bonus voice track!
えー、フルセットのね、なんかちょっと欲しいって、みんな思ったんじゃないでしょうか。ぜひ、ゲットしてみてくだい。ボイスも...
I'm sure you all felt like you wanted the full set. Please get it. The voice too...
もね、心を込めて撮ります！よろしくお願いします！
I'll also do my best to create this with all my heart! Please look forward to it!
生誕グッズは22時カートオープンです！
The birthday merchandise cart opens at 22:00!
みなさん、ぜひ、ゲットしてください！お願いします！
Everyone, please make sure to get them! Thank you!
さらにさらに、重大告知があります！
And furthermore, there is a major announcement!
なんとそれは… ズンズンズンズンズン… はい！新曲があります！
And that is... drumroll... Yes! I have a new song!
その新曲を発表するにあたって、なんと、
In announcing this new song, what's more,
とか、ちょっと今回スペシャルな方からコメントをいただいてるみたいなんだけど、
we've actually received a comment from a very special guest this time...
誰なんだろう？ちょっとノエルわかんないな。誰でしょうか？
I wonder who it could be? Noel doesn't know at all. Who is it?
え、待って！わあ！すごいキラキラしてる！
Wait! Wow! It's so sparkly!
こんまっする〜！
Konmassuru~!
白銀ノエルさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Shirogane Noel-san, happy birthday!
そして、団員の皆さん、配信を楽しんでいらっしゃいますか？
And to all the members of the Order, are you enjoying the stream?
大分県知事の佐藤樹一郎です。
I am Kiichiro Sato, the Governor of Oita Prefecture.
大分県応援団鳥めじろんです！ / なに？ちっち！
I'm Mejiron, the Oita Prefecture Cheerleader Bird! / What? Tiny!
この度は新曲の発表もおめでとうございます。 / ありがとうございます！
Congratulations on the announcement of your new song as well. / Thank you very much!
今回、私がノエルさんの新曲のタイトル発表を任せていただけることになりました。 / ええ！して、してくれるんですか？
This time, I have been entrusted with announcing the title of Noel-san's new song. / What! You're going to do it for me?
それでは、早速、曲名を発表したいと思います。 / お願いします！
Now, without further ado, I would like to announce the title of the song. / Please do!
その名も、VAVAVA!バーチャル大分 / バーチャル大分！わーい！
The title is... "VAVAVA! Virtual Oita"! / Virtual Oita! Yay!
そうですね、「バーチャル大分」と入っていますので、大分をバーチャルで楽しめるような歌なのかな。 / はい！そうです！
Well, since it includes "Virtual Oita," I suppose it's a song that lets you enjoy Oita virtually. / Yes! That's right!
はい！大分のオススメたくさんありますよ！
Yes! Oita has many recommended attractions!
まずは何と言っても温泉です！大分県は源泉数、湧出量ともに全国1位ですから。 / 温泉、最高です！
First and foremost is the hot springs! Oita Prefecture ranks first in Japan in both the number of hot spring sources and the volume of water discharged. / Hot springs are the best!
他にも関アジや関サバ、かぼすブリ、おおいた和牛、からあげなんかも食の魅力も満載ですね。 / 美味しい！最高です！
Additionally, there are Seki-aji, Seki-saba, Kabosu-buri, Oita Wagyu, Karaage, and many other culinary charms. / Delicious! It's the best!
ぜひ、皆さんにも味わっていただきたいです！ / はい！
I'd love for everyone to experience them! / Yes!
ノエルさん、大分を代表して応援しちょんけん、これからも大分県のPRを頼むけんな！ / ええ！ありがとうございます！
Noel-san, I'm supporting you on behalf of Oita, so please keep promoting Oita Prefecture! / Wow! Thank you very much!
新曲、しんけん楽しみにしちょんけん！それでは、おつまっする〜！ / おつ、おつまっする〜！
I'm truly looking forward to the new song! Well then, otsumassuru~! / Otsu, otsumassuru~!
同じ団員同士頑張ろう！ / めじろんも！おつまっする！
Let's do our best as fellow Order members! / Mejiron too! Otsumassuru!
めじ、おつまっする、おつまっする、ということで、
Meji, otsumassuru, otsumassuru! So, anyway...
まさかの、意外や意外！大分県知事の佐藤樹一郎さんに、新曲のタイトル発表と応援のコメントをいただきました！ありがとうございました！
To my surprise, what an unexpected turn of events! Kiichiro Sato, the Governor of Oita Prefecture, announced the title of my new song and sent me a supportive message! Thank you so much!
これ、本当にノエルちゃんびっくりで、本当にこれ、サプライズなんですけど。いや、本当にありがとうございます。まさか、こんな日が来るなんて。
I was really surprised by this, it was truly a complete surprise. Thank you so much. I never thought a day like this would come.
本当にね、すごい方から応援していただいて嬉しいですね。ちょっと団長、何が起こったのか最初わからず。
I'm so happy to receive support from such an amazing person. At first, I had no idea what was happening.
しかも、めじろんも横にいて。あのね、緑の、そう、いましたね。すごく可愛かったなと思います。
And Mejiron was there next to him. You know, that green bird. He was there. It was so cute.
本当にね、ずっと団長、大分育ちで、大分の魅力をバーっと配信で個人的に、
Actually, Noel was raised in Oita, and I've just been sharing Oita's charms on stream personally,
言っているだけなんですけれど。
just as my own personal thing.
いや、本当に日頃大分の魅力を伝えてきてよかったなと思います。
But I'm so glad I've been sharing the appeal of Oita up until now.
もちろん、これからも個人的に、特に何か大きなことがあるわけではなく、個人的に、
Of course, I will continue to do so personally—not that there is any major official thing, just personally—
団長、大分の魅力を伝えていきたいなと思いますので、
I want to continue sharing the charms of Oita as Noel,
皆さんもまだ大分に行ったことがない人はぜひ大分に行ってみてください！
so for those who haven't been to Oita yet, please be sure to visit!
いいところだよ！
It's a wonderful place!
はい、ということで、新曲を歌っちゃいたいと思います！聞いてください！「VAVAVA!バーチャル大分」！
Alright, so now, I'd like to perform the new song! Please listen to "VAVAVA! Virtual Oita"!
説明しよう。
Let me explain.
バーチャル大分とは、バーチャル九州の北東部に位置する広大な大地。
Virtual Oita is a vast land located in the northeastern part of Virtual Kyushu.
現実の大分県に限りなく近い、地上の楽園。
A paradise on Earth, infinitely close to the real Oita Prefecture.
人はその地を、バーチャル大分と呼ぶ！
People call that land Virtual Oita!
バババ バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Va-va-va Virtual Oita, unleashing it to the world!
バババ バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
Va-va-va Virtual Oita, boiling the hot spring waters!
君と バーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running all over Virtual Oita with you!
バババ バーチャル大分 大分どーん！
Va-va-va Virtual Oita, Oita Boom!
VAVAVA! バーチャル大分
VAVAVA! Virtual Oita
大分どーん！
Oita Boom!
君は降り立つ 魅惑の地獄の入り口
You descend upon the entrance to the enchanting Hells
絶えず湯沸く 誘惑の地
A land of temptation where hot water constantly boils
海 かまど 白池 血の池
Umi, Kamado, Shiraike, Chinoike
鬼石坊主 鬼山 龍巻 パーン！
Onishi-bozu, Oniyama, Tatsumaki, Bang!
とりてん とりめし やせうま だんご汁
Toriten, Torimeshi, Yaseuma, Dango-jiru
中津からあげ 冷麺 関アジ 関サバ
Nakatsu Karaage, Reimen, Seki-aji, Seki-saba
かぼす あつめし まだまだ入るよ
Kabosu, Atsumeshi, there's still room for more!
鉄の胃袋 大魔神
In this iron stomach of a Great Demon God!
行こうぜ久住高原 湯煙の温泉
Let's go to Kuju Highland, a hot spring of rising steam!
高崎山に金鱗湖
Takasakiyama and Lake Kinrin
青の洞門 由布川渓谷
Ao no Doumon and Yufugawa Canyon
進め 稲積水中鍾乳洞
Forward to the Inazumi Underwater Cave!
果てしなき旅 努力 演奏
An endless journey, effort, and performance!
たどり着く先 食べる 弁当
Our destination, where we'll eat bento!
時空を超えた奇跡の 大地
A miraculous land transcending space and time...
バーチャル大分 いくぞー！
Virtual Oita! Here we go!
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Virtual Oita, released to the world!
バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
Virtual Oita, heating up the hot springs!
君と バーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you!
バーチャル大分 大分 どーん！
Virtual Oita, Oita, boom!
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Virtual Oita, released to the world!
バーチャル大分 食べ尽くす
Virtual Oita, eating it all up!
君と バーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you!
バーチャル大分 大分 どーん！
Virtual Oita, Oita, boom!
大分 どーん！
Oita, boom!
よだきい しゃあしい えーらしい
Tiresome, noisy, so cute!
しんけん やおねえ ふうがわりい
Very tough, eccentric!
なしか むげねえ せせろしい
Why? Pitiful, restless!
だけどあんた 今なにしちょん？
But what are you doing right now?
説明しよう！ バーチャル大分観光大使とは
Let me explain! The Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassadors...
バーチャル大分への深い郷土愛を持ち
...possess a deep love for the homeland of Virtual Oita...
その魅力を余すところなく伝え続ける存在
...and continue to convey its charms to the fullest!
人はその大使の名を バーチャル大分観光大使と呼ぶ！
People call these ambassadors, "Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassadors"!
バーチャル O-O-I-T-A I wanna be
Virtual O-O-I-T-A, I wanna be
のっちょる？ だんちょー 観光大使！
Are you on board? Captain, Tourism Ambassador!
バーチャル O-O-I-T-A I wanna be
Virtual O-O-I-T-A, I wanna be
のっちょる？ だんちょー 観光大使（自称）
Are you on board? Captain, Tourism Ambassador (self-proclaimed)!
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Virtual Oita, released to the world!
バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
Virtual Oita, heating up the hot springs!
君と バーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you!
バーチャル大分 大分 どーん！
Virtual Oita, Oita, boom!
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Virtual Oita, released to the world!
バーチャル大分 食べ尽くす
Virtual Oita, eating it all up!
君と バーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you!
バーチャル大分 大分 どーん！
Virtual Oita, Oita, boom!
大分 どーん！
Oita, boom!
新曲MV公開、この後すぐ！
[On-Screen: New MV release, right after this!]
団員さん！今年も お誕生日をお祝いしてくれて本当にありがとう〜♥
新衣装や表情など…どうだったかな？？！
Order members! Thank you so much for celebrating my birthday again this year! ♥
How did you like my new outfit and expressions?!
少しでも好き〜〜ってなってくれたらとっても嬉しいです。来年も一緒に時間を過ごせますように…☆ 大好きだよ〜♪
Noe 2025.11.24
I'd be so happy if you liked them even a little! I hope we can spend time together next year too... ☆
Love you all! ♪ - Noe 2025.11.24